Guide to the Washington Metro Oral History Project collection, 1975-2021 MS2214
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Washington Metro Oral History Project collection
1975-2002, 2021
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Schrag, Zachary M.
MS2214
6.75 Linear Feet
This collection consists of oral history interviews conducted by Dr. Zachary Schrag. These oral histories relate to the history of the Washington Metro.
Restrictions on Access
The following oral histories are sealed until the earlier of narrator's death or January 1, 2050: Francois, Francis; Bowie, Md.; February 25, 2002; Kulash, Damien; Washington, D.C.; June 20, 2001. The following oral history is sealed until January 1, 2050: Herman, William; telephone; March 20, 2000. The following oral history is sealed until January 3, 2050: Thresher, Sprague; telephone; January 3, 2000
Acquisition Information
Gift of Zachary Schrag.
Historical or Biographical Note
This collection is composed of oral histories conducted by Dr. Zachary Schrag. Dr. Schrag is a history professor at George Mason University in Fairfax County, Virginia. Dr. Schrag conducted these interviews as research for his Ph.D dissertation. His dissertation was eventually published in 2006 as the book The Great Society Subway: A history of the Washington Metro.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection is composed of compact discs and several transcripts of oral histories. Dr. Zachary Schrag conducted these oral histories with people involved in the design, development, and construction of the Metro in Washington, D.C. Dr. Schrag interviewed many people significantly involved with the creation of the Metro including local politicians Gilbert Gude and Walter Fauntroy; the first Secretary of Transportation Alan Boyd, engineer Howard Lyon; architect John Insco Williams; Commission of Fine Arts member John Carl Warnecke; and lawyer and transportation activist Peter Craig.
Collection Organization
Organized into two series: Interview recordings and Interview transcripts and notes.
Link for uploaded content
The recordings and some transcripts of a portion of these oral histories are available in the Internet Archive. Internet Archive search
Washington (D.C.); Transportation; Transportation -- Washington Metropolitan Area; Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; Stolzenbach, C. Darwin; Pfanstiehl, Cody
- Interview recordings and transcripts (at this time not all interviews have transcripts), 1975-2002, 2021; MS2214 Series 1; 4.25 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains oral history interviews conducted by Dr. Zachary Schrag. These interviews range in date from 1975-2002 and 2021.
  link for uploaded interviews
  The recording and when available the transcripts of these oral histories are available in the Internet Archive. Material from this collection can be found at https://archive.org/details/gwulibraries?sort=titleSorter&&and[]=subject%3A%22MS2214%22
  - Joe Alexander [1/2], 01/29/2001 (Box 1, Item 1)
    General note
    Interview: 47 minutes, 0 seconds; Intro: 11 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Joe Alexander [2/2], 01/29/2001 (Box 1, Item 2)
    Interview: 43 minutes, 26 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Stan Allan [1/4], 07/26/2000 (Box 1, Item 3)
    Interview: 51 minutes, 48 seconds; Intro: 15 seconds
  - Stan Allan [2/4], 07/26/2000 (Box 1, Item 4)
    Interview: 49 minutes, 26 seconds; Intro: 14 seconds
  - Stan Allan [3/4], 07/26/2000 (Box 1, Item 5)
    Interview: 44 minutes, 56 seconds; Intro: 14 seconds
  - Stan Allan [4/4], 07/26/2000 (Box 1, Item 6)
    Interview: 49 minutes, 30 seconds; Intro: 13 seconds
  - Charles Atherton [1/2], 02/15/2000 (Box 1, Item 7)
    Interview: 43 minutes, 29 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Charles Atherton [2/2], 02/15/2000 (Box 1, Item 8)
    Interview: 21 minutes, 39 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Cleatus Barnett [1/2], 01/25/2001 (Box 1, Item 9)
    Interview: 56 minutes, 43 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Cleatus Barnett [2/2], 01/25/2001 (Box 1, Item 10)
    Interview: 52 minutes, 46 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - John L. Beerman, 05/19/2001 (Box 1, Item 11)
    Interview: 46 minutes, 32 seconds; interview conducted by telephone.
  - William Boleyn [1/2], 04/26/2000 (Box 1, Item 12)
    Interview: 37 minutes, 51 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - William Boleyn [2/2], 04/26/2000 (Box 1, Item 13)
    Interview: 30 minutes, 36 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - William Boleyn [1/2], 05/10/2000 (Box 1, Item 14)
    Interview: 53 minutes, 35 seconds; Intro: 9 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - William Boleyn [2/2], 05/10/2000 (Box 1, Item 15)
    Interview: 49 minutes, 21 seconds; Intro: 9 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Alan Boyd, 10/02/2001 (Box 1, Item 16)
    Interview: 50 minutes, 42 seconds; interview conducted by telephone.
  - Ellen Bozman, 01/12/2004 (Box 1, Item 17)
    Interview: 55 minutes, 10 seconds
  - James A. Caywood [1/3], 01/18/2000 (Box 1, Item 18)
    Interview: 41 minutes, 23 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Frederick, Md.
  - James A. Caywood [2/3], 01/18/2000 (Box 1, Item 19)
    Interview: 40 minutes, 42 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Frederick, Md.
  - James A. Caywood [3/3], 01/18/2000 (Box 1, Item 20)
    Interview: 39 minutes, 31 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Frederick, Md.
  - Richard Chenoweth [part1](Coming soon), 2021 August 21; MS2214 Series 1
  - Richard Chenoweth [part 2] (coming soon), 2021 August 21; MS2214 Series 1
  - Peter Craig [1/2], 11/05/1999 (Box 1, Item 21)
    Interview: 35 minutes, 38 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Peter Craig [2/2], 11/05/1999 (Box 1, Item 22)
    Interview: 32 minutes, 56 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Peter Craig [1/2], 06/12/2002 (Box 1, Item 23)
    Interview: 38 minutes, 42 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Peter Craig [2/2], 06/12/2002 (Box 1, Item 24)
    Interview: 34 minutes, 12 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Tom Deen [1/3], 12/01/1999 (Box 1, Item 25)
    Interview: 46 minutes, 48 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Stevensville, Md.
  - Tom Deen [2/3], 12/01/1999 (Box 1, Item 26)
    Interview: 46 minutes, 4 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Stevensville, Md.
  - Tom Deen [3/3], 12/01/1999 (Box 1, Item 27)
    Interview: 46 minutes, 57 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Stevensville, Md.
  - Roy Dodge [1/2], 02/15/2001 (Box 2, Item 1)
    Interview: 39 minutes, 28 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Ft. Belvoir, Va.
  - Roy Dodge [2/2], 02/15/2001 (Box 2, Item 2)
    Interview: 37 minutes, 39 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Ft. Belvoir, Va.
  - Walter Fauntroy [1/2], 10/12/2001 (Box 2, Item 3)
    Interview: 40 minutes, 19 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Walter Fauntroy [2/2], 10/12/2001 (Box 2, Item 4)
    Interview: 39 minutes, 59 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - John Fondersmith [1/2], 05/30/2001 (Box 2, Item 5)
    Interview: 59 minutes, 9 seconds; Intro: 10 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - John Fondersmith [2/2], 05/30/2001 (Box 2, Item 6)
    Interview: 59 minutes, 14 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Vernon Garrett [1/3], 10/26/2000 (Box 2, Item 7)
    Interview: 45 minutes, 53 seconds; Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Phoenix, Md.
  - Vernon Garrett [2/3], 10/26/2000 (Box 2, Item 8)
    Interview: 45 minutes, 11 seconds; Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Phoenix, Md.
  - Vernon Garrett [3/3], 10/26/2000 (Box 2, Item 9)
    Interview: 47 minutes, 18 seconds; Intro 10 seconds; interview conducted in Phoenix, Md.
  - Ben Gilbert [1/2], 03/19/2002 (Box 2, Item 10)
    Interview: 60 minutes, 18 seconds; Intro 10 seconds; telephone interview
  - Ben Gilbert [2/2], 03/19/2002 (Box 2, Item 11)
    Interview: 60 minutes, 9 seconds; Intro 10 seconds; telephone interview
  - Gilbert Gude [1/2], 08/02/2000 (Box 2, Item 12)
    Interview: 57 minutes, 10 seconds; Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Bethesda, Md.
  - Gilbert Gude [2/2], 08/02/2000 (Box 2, Item 13)
    Interview: 57 minutes, 16 seconds; Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Bethesda, Md.
  - Herbert Harris [1/2], 03/13/2001 (Box 2, Item 14)
    Interview: 47 minutes, 0 seconds; Intro 11 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Herbert Harris [2/2], 03/13/2001 (Box 2, Item 15)
    Interview: 34 minutes, 47 seconds; Intro 12 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Herbert Harris [1/2], 03/02/2001 (Box 2, Item 16)
    Interview: 36 minutes, 5 seconds; Intro 13 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Herbert Harris [2/2], 03/02/2001 (Box 2, Item 17)
    Interview: 35 minutes, 31 seconds; Intro 12 seconds; interview conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Richard Heck, 10/30/2001 (Box 2, Item 18)
    Interview: 57 minutes, 4 seconds
  - Richard Heddinger (Part I) [1/3], 10/11/2000 (Box 2, Item 19)
    Interview: 51 minutes, 42 seconds; Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Bowie Md.
  - Richard Heddinger (Part I) [2/3], 10/11/2000 (Box 2, Item 20)
    Interview: 51 minutes, 24 seconds; Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Bowie Md.
  - Richard Heddinger (Part I) [3/3], 10/11/2000 (Box 2, Item 21)
    Interview: 39 minutes, 52 seconds; Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Bowie Md.
  - Richard Heddinger (Part II), 10/11/2000 (Box 2, Item 22)
    Interview: 51 minutes, 44 seconds; interview conducted in Bowie Md.
  - Larry Heflin [1/3], 09/25/2000 (Box 2, Item 23)
    Interview: 52 minutes, 58 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Cabin John, Md.
  - Larry Heflin [2/3], 09/25/2000 (Box 2, Item 24)
    Interview: 54 minutes, 40 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Cabin John, Md.
  - Larry Heflin [3/3], 09/25/2000 (Box 2, Item 25)
    Interview: 52 minutes, 16 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in Cabin John, Md.
  - Delmer Ison [1/3], 10/23/2000 (Box 2, Item 26)
    Interview: 48 minutes, 10 seconds, Intro 18 seconds
  - Delmer Ison [2/3], 10/23/2000 (Box 2, Item 27)
    Interview: 46 minutes, 52 seconds, Intro 17 seconds
  - Delmer Ison [3/3], 10/23/2000 (Box 3, Item 1)
    Interview: 38 minutes, 28 seconds, Intro 17 seconds
  - Ivailo Karadimov (coming soon), 2021 July 07; MS2214 Series 1
    Scope and Contents
    This interview was conducted with both Ivailo Karadimov and Jeffrey Winstel
  - Robert Keith [1/2], 01/19/2000 (Box 3, Item 2)
    Interview: 47 minutes, 52 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; conducted by telephone
  - Robert Keith [2/2], 01/19/2000 (Box 3, Item 3)
    Interview: 44 minutes, 52 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; conducted by telephone
  - Egil Krogh, 02/08/2001 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - William Lam [1/2], 08/21/2000 (Box 3, Item 5)
    Interview: 59 minutes, 28 seconds, Intro 8 seconds; conducted in Cambridge, Mass.
  - William Lam [2/2], 08/21/2000 (Box 3, Item 6)
    Interview: 59 minutes, 19 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; conducted in Cambridge, Mass.
  - Theodore Lutz, 10/06/2000 (Box 3, Item 7)
    Interview: 53 minutes, 19 seconds, Intro 11 seconds; conducted in Washington, D.C.
  - Howard Lyon [1/3], 03/13/2000 (Box 3, Item 8)
    Interview: 47 minutes, 1 seconds, Intro 11 seconds; conducted in Gaithersburg, Md.
  - Howard Lyon [2/3], 03/13/2000 (Box 3, Item 9)
    Interview: 45 minutes, 52 seconds, Intro 8 seconds; conducted in Gaithersburg, Md.
  - Howard Lyon [3/3], 03/13/2000 (Box 3, Item 10)
    Interview: 44 minutes, 28 seconds, Intro 8 seconds; conducted in Gaithersburg, Md.
  - Stephen Nordlinger, 12/06/2001 (Box 3, Item 11)
    Interview: 49 minutes, 21 seconds; conducted in Chevy Chase, Md.
  - Edward Northrop [1/2], 06/08/2000 (Box 3, Item 12)
    Interview: 32 minutes, 16 seconds, Intro 8 seconds
  - Edward Northrop [2/2], 06/08/2000 (Box 3, Item 13)
    Interview: 30 minutes, 56 seconds, Intro 7 seconds
  - Robert Peskin [1/2], 09/06/2000 (Box 3, Item 14)
    Interview: 40 minutes, 0 seconds, Intro 12 seconds
  - Robert Peskin [2/2], 09/06/2000 (Box 3, Item 15)
    Interview: 39 minutes, 9 seconds, Intro 9 seconds
  - Cody Pfanstiehl, 12/15/1999 (Box 3, Item 16)
    Interview: 57 minutes, 30 seconds; conducted in Silver Spring, Md.
  - Cody Pfanstiehl [1/2], 01/04/2000 (Box 3, Item 17)
    Interview: 44 minutes, 37 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; conducted in Silver Spring, Md.
  - Cody Pfanstiehl [2/2], 01/04/2000 (Box 3, Item 18)
    Interview: 36 minutes, 28 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; conducted in Silver Spring, Md.
  - Cody Pfanstiehl [1/2], 09/20/2000 (Box 3, Item 19)
    Interview: 38 minutes, 40 seconds, Intro 7 seconds; conducted in Silver Spring, Md.
  - Cody Pfanstiehl [2/2], 09/20/2000 (Box 3, Item 20)
    Interview: 41 minutes, 42 seconds, Intro 8 seconds; conducted in Silver Spring, Md.
  - James Phippard, 10/12/1999 (Box 3, Item 21)
    Interview: 40 minutes, 31 seconds; conducted in Washington, D.C. A second interview is in box 9 folder 1.
  - Mathew Platt [1/2], 09/27/2000 (Box 3, Item 22)
    Interview: 38 minutes, 16 seconds, Intro 10 seconds
  - Mathew Platt [2/2], 09/27/2000 (Box 3, Item 23)
    Interview: 35 minutes, 51 seconds, Intro 9 seconds
  - Jean Provost, 10/01/1999 (Box 3, Item 24)
    Interview: 39 minutes, 40 seconds
  - Barbara Richardson (coming soon), 2021 August 04; MS2214 Series 1
    General
    Barbara Richardson in 2021 was Executive Vice President, External Relations, Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority
    At the time of the map redesign discussed in the interview, Richardson was the Assistant General Manager of Customer Service, Communications and Marketing
  - Ralph Rohner, 09/15/1999 (Box 3, Item 25)
    Interview: 53 minutes, 36 seconds
  - Kevin Sarring and Emil Kish [1/2], 02/10/2000 (Box 4, Item 1)
    Interview: 42 minutes, 44 seconds, Intro 11 seconds
  - Kevin Sarring and Emil Kish [2/2], 02/10/2000 (Box 4, Item 2)
    Interview: 35 minutes, 36 seconds, Intro 11 seconds
  - Joseph Saunders [1/2], 11/09/2000 (Box 4, Item 3)
    Interview: 47 minutes, 0 seconds, Intro 8 seconds
  - Joseph Saunders [2/2], 11/09/2000 (Box 4, Item 4)
    Interview: 42 minutes, 19 seconds, Intro 8 seconds
  - Edson Tennyson [1/2], 08/24/1999 (Box 4, Item 5)
    Interview: 54 minutes, 59 seconds, Intro 9 seconds
  - Edson Tennyson [2/2], 08/24/1999 (Box 4, Item 6)
    Interview: 51 minutes, 19 seconds, Intro 10 seconds
  - Edson Tennyson [1/3], 10/11/1999 (Box 4, Item 7)
    Interview: 52 minutes, 53 seconds, Intro 9 seconds
  - Edson Tennyson [2/3], 10/11/1999 (Box 4, Item 8)
    Interview: 52 minutes, 28 seconds, Intro 9 seconds
  - Edson Tennyson [3/3], 10/11/1999 (Box 4, Item 9)
    Interview: 50 minutes, 24 seconds, Intro 10 seconds
  - Massimo Vignelli [1/2], 10/03/2000 (Box 4, Item 10)
    Interview: 47 minutes, 57 seconds, Intro 9 seconds
  - Massimo Vignelli [2/2], 10/03/2000 (Box 4, Item 11)
    Interview: 34 minutes, 47 seconds, Intro 9 seconds
  - John Carl Warnecke [1/3], 01/04/2002 (Box 4, Item 12)
    Interview: 41 minutes, 47 seconds, Intro 10 seconds; interview conducted in San Francisco, Ca.
  - John Carl Warnecke [2/3], 01/04/2002 (Box 4, Item 13)
    Interview: 54 minutes, 14 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in San Francisco, Ca.
  - John Carl Warnecke [3/3], 01/04/2002 (Box 4, Item 14)
    Interview: 30 minutes, 42 seconds, Intro 9 seconds; interview conducted in San Francisco, Ca.
  - John Warrington [1/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 15)
    Interview: 57 minutes, 03 seconds; 7 second intro
  - John Warrington [2/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 16)
    Interview: 55 minutes, 26 seconds; 6 second intro
  - John Warrington [3/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 17)
    Interview: 55 minutes, 57 seconds; 6 second intro
  - John Warrington [4/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 18)
    Interview: 47 minutes, 54 seconds; 7 second intro
  - John Warrington [5/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 19)
    Interview: 52 minutes, 29 seconds; 6 second intro
  - John Warrington [6/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 20)
    Interview: 49 minutes, 37 seconds; 6 second intro
  - John Warrington [7/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 21)
    Interview: 51 minutes, 23 seconds; 6 second intro
  - John Warrington [8/8], 04/09/2001 (Box 4, Item 22)
    Interview: 48 minutes, 57 seconds; 6 second intro
  - John Insco Williams [1/4], 01/03/2001 (Box 4, Item 23)
    Interview: 53 minutes, 51 seconds, Intro 14 seconds
  - John Insco Williams [2/4], 01/03/2001 (Box 4, Item 24)
    Interview: 51 minutes, 49 seconds, Intro 15 seconds
  - John Insco Williams [3/4], 01/03/2001 (Box 4, Item 25)
    Interview: 52 minutes, 5 seconds, Intro 16 seconds
  - John Insco Williams [4/4], 01/03/2001 (Box 4, Item 26)
    Interview: 48 minutes, 52 seconds, Intro 15 seconds
  - Jeffery Winstel (coming soon), 2021 July 07; MS2214 Series 1
  - Lance Wyman, 10/23/2000 (Box 4, Item 27)
    Interview: 26 minutes, 31 seconds
  - Jerome Alper [1/2], 10/08/1998 (Box 5, Item 1)
    Interview in Chevy Chase, Maryland: 44 minutes, 16 seconds; 9 second intro
  - Jerome Alper [2/2], 10/08/1998 (Box 5, Item 2)
    Interview in Chevy Chase, Maryland: 31 minutes, 14 seconds; 7 second intro
  - Cleatus Barnett [1/2], 01/25/2001 (Box 5, Item 3)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 56 minutes, 42 seconds
  - Cleatus Barnett [2/2], 01/25/2001 (Box 5, Item 4)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 52 minutes, 46 seconds
  - Kent Cooper [1/2], 12/06/1999 (Box 5, Item 5)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 58 minutes, 04 seconds; 6 second intro
    Biographical / Historical
    Kent Cooper died January 2018. His oral history is open to the public.
  - Kent Cooper [2/2], 12/06/1999 (Box 5, Item 6)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 58 minutes, 56 seconds; 7 second intro
    Kent Cooper died January 2018. His oral history interview is open to the public.
  - Tom Deen, 10/13/2002 (Box 5, Item 7)
    Interview in Stevensville, Maryland: 41 minutes, 51 seconds; 6 second intro
  - Barbara Franco, 11/06/2001 (Box 5, Item 8)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 48 minutes, 13 seconds
  - Francis Francois [1/4], 02/25/2002 (Box R1, Folder 2)
    Interview in Bowie, Maryland: 39 minutes, 38 seconds; 8 second into
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted for use until the earlier of the interviewee's death or January 1, 2050.
  - Francis Francois [2/4], 02/25/2002 (Box R1, Folder 2)
    Interview in Bowie, Maryland: 35 minutes, 23 seconds; 8 second into
  - Francis Francois [3/4], 02/25/2002 (Box R1, Folder 2)
    Interview in Bowie, Maryland: 58 minutes, 40 seconds; 7 second into
  - Francis Francois [4/4], 02/25/2002 (Box R1, Folder 2)
    Interview in Bowie, Maryland: 9 minutes, 48 seconds; 8 second into
  - William Herman [1/2], 03/30/2000 (Box R1, Folder 3)
    Interview by telephone: 46 minutes, 11 seconds; 5 second into
    Restricted for use until January 1, 2050.
  - William Herman [2/2], 03/30/2000 (Box R1, Folder 3)
    Interview by telephone: 47 minutes, 54 seconds; 5 second into
  - Damien Kulash [1/2], 06/20/2001 (Box R1, Folder 4)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 58 minutes, 23 seconds; 6 second into
  - Damien Kulash [2/2], 06/20/2001 (Box R1, Folder 4)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 42 minutes, 11 seconds; 6 second into
  - Roberts Owen [1/2], 07/19/2000 (Box 5, Item 17)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 30 minutes, 47 seconds; 7 second into
  - Roberts Owen [2/2], 07/19/2000 (Box 5, Item 18)
    Interview in Washington, D.C.: 31 minutes, 55 seconds; 6 second into
  - Robert Patricelli, 05/16/2002 (Box 5, Item 19)
    Interview by telephone: 40 minutes, 26 seconds
  - Edwin Schell [1/2], 12/10/1998 (Box 5, Item 20)
    Interview in Baltimore, Maryland: 43 minutes, 57 seconds; 9 second intro
  - Edwin Schell [2/2], 12/10/1998 (Box 5, Item 21)
    Interview in Baltimore, Maryland: 40 minutes, 57 seconds; 8 second intro
  - Edwin Schell, 01/07/1999 (Box 5, Item 22)
    Interview in Baltimore, Maryland: 55 minutes, 28 seconds
  - Mel Siegel [1/3], 12/28/2002 (Box 5, Item 23)
    Interview in Chevy Chase, Maryland: 49 minutes, 41 seconds; 6 second intro
  - Mel Siegel [2/3], 12/28/2002 (Box 5, Item 24)
    Interview in Chevy Chase, Maryland: 50 minutes, 7 seconds; 6 second intro
  - Mel Siegel [3/3], 12/28/2002 (Box 5, Item 25)
    Interview in Chevy Chase, Maryland: 33 minutes, 57 seconds; 6 second intro
  - Elmer Staats, 01/26/2000 (Box 5, Item 26)
    Interview in Chevy Chase, Maryland: 53 minutes, 23 seconds
  - Sprague Thresher [1/2], 01/03/2000 (Box R1, Folder 5)
    Interview by telephone: 44 minutes, 13 seconds; 6 second intro
    Restricted for use until January 3, 2050.
  - Sprague Thresher [2/2], 01/03/2000 (Box R1, Folder 5)
    Interview by telephone: 49 minutes, 51 seconds; 6 second intro
  - George Wickstrom [1/2], 10/15/2001 (Box 6, Item 3)
    Interview in Kennsington, Maryland: 41 minutes, 46 seconds
  - George Wickstrom [2/2], 10/15/2001 (Box 6, Item 4)
    Interview in Kennsington, Maryland: 34 minutes, 13 seconds
  - Basil Whitener [1/2], 11/13/1982 (Box 7, Item 1)
    This is a copy made by the Special Collections Research Center of an interview recorded for Metro 2001, Inc.'s Metro History Project. The original recording is part of MS2034, The Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority: Metro History Project Collection.
  - Basil Whitener [2/2] and Edwin Seeger, 11/13/1982 - 11/18/1982 (Box 7, Item 2)
  - Harry Weese and Lyle Fitch, 09/02/1981 - 06/03/1982 (Box 7, Item 3)
  - John Nevius and Sterling Tucker, 11/10/1981 - 11/20/1981 (Box 7, Item 4)
  - Sammy Abbott and James Gleason, 01/07/1982 - 05/12/1983 (Box 7, Item 5)
  - Cleatus Barnett and Walter Fauntroy, 11/05/1981 - 01/18/1982 (Box 7, Item 6)
  - Alan Boyd and George Hartzog, 06/23/1981 - 08/11/1982 (Box 7, Item 7)
  - Phillip G. Hammer CH NCPC 1968-1969, 12/22/1982 (Box 7, Item 8)
  - Max Wehrly, 06/09/1982 (Box 7, Item 9)
  - Wilfred Owen, 02/09/1982 (Box 7, Item 10)
  - Herbert Harris and Joseph Fisher, 10/21/1981 - 11/18/1981 (Box 7, Item 11)
    This is a copy made by the Special Collections Research Center of an interview recorded for Metro 2001, Inc.'s Metro History Project. The original recording is part of MS2034, The Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority: Metro History Project Collection. The cassette label also lists the name Stolzenbach.
  - Cody Pfanstiehl, 04/06/1983 (Box 7, Item 12)
  - Warren Quenstedt, 11/06/1982 (Box 7, Item 13)
  - Charles Horsky and Paul Watt, 10/02/1981 - 12/02/1981 (Box 7, Item 14)
  - Herbert Wells, 07/23/1975 (Box 7, Item 15)
  - Hugh Wynn, 06/02/1981 (Box 7, Item 16)
  - Carlton Sickles and Leo Urbanski, 10/26/1981 (Box 7, Item 17)
  - Charles Conrad, undated (Box 7, Item 18)
  - William Finley, 05/20/1982 (Box 7, Item 19)
  - James Phippard, 10/26/1999 (Box 9, Item 1)
    Interview in Washington, DC; length 42:07. Another interivew is in box 3 folder 21.
  - Martin Wohl [1/4], 05/02/2002 (Box 9, Item 2)
    Interview in Springfield Virginia; 54 minutes, 43 seconds, intro 10 seconds
  - Martin Wohl [2/4], 05/02/2002 (Box 9, Item 3)
    Interview in Springfield Virginia; 50 minutes, 30 seconds, intro 9 seconds
  - Martin Wohl [3/4], 05/02/2002 (Box 9, Item 4)
    Interview in Springfield Virginia; 49 minutes, 17 seconds, intro 9 seconds
  - Martin Wohl [4/4], 05/02/2002 (Box 9, Item 5)
    Interview in Springfield Virginia; 41 minutes, 56 seconds, intro 10 seconds
- Interview transcripts and notes, MS2214 Series 2; 0.50 Linear feet